Daniel R. Zervoudakes

Greater Philadelphia Area (609) 634-6660 dan.zervoudakes@gmail.com https://www.github.com/DanZiti https://www.linkedin.com/in/drzerv

Summary

- Evolving interactive developer fluent in JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3 and some PHP
- 3+ years proven experience with responsive development as related to web, eDetailing and eLearning applications
- Utilize the latest available web capabilities while also seasoned in supporting legacy browsers including Internet Explorer 7 and "quirks mode"

Technical Proficiencies

 Programming Languages, Frameworks and Content Management Systems: JavaScript (raw, jQuery, custom libraries), HTML5, CSS3, XHTML/XML, PHP, WordPress CMS, SharePoint, Google

Analytics API, Photoshop JavaScript API

eDetailing Packages: Veeva CRM, (Salesforce), iQ.mercury, Exploria

• Software Applications: Photoshop CS6/CC, Illustrator CS6/CC, Coda 2

(Transmit), Articulate Storyline, Excel, Word, PowerPoint,

Outlook

Version Control Systems: GitHub (Git), Subversion (Cornerstone, Tortoise)

Professional Experience

Senior Interactive Developer

Bristol-Myers Squibb (BMStudio), Plainsboro, NJ

June 2014 — Present

- Responsible for developing web-based interactive visual aids (IVAs) and animations on iPad with retina display while providing a high-quality user experience
- Set up a responsive widget for the ORENCIA® (abatacept) informational website turning static images into a sequential animation
- Developed a custom swiping mechanism to increase usability within Veeva CRM presentations on iOS
- Created a script that dynamically generates the appropriate slide references in a presentation and automatically updates applicable superscripts within the markup
- Built a script for use with the Photoshop JavaScript API which batch-exports slide thumbnail images at the appropriate dimensions and file format for use within the Veeva CRM shell
- Developed a jQuery "doubleTap" plugin for use in our visual aids
- Successfully converted multiple waves of European Exploria-based visual aids into Veeva CRM packages leveraging an in-house PHP engine
- Contributed to the development of a custom in-house JavaScript library for use within our IVAs
- Implemented a customizable "pinch-zoom" protocol for use within our IVAs via "iScroll"
- Effectively drive several projects simultaneously through successful implementation from start to finish while coordinating essential project tasks and estimates between the teams in Plainsboro, Tampa, and Europe
- Experience interacting directly with business partners and brand champions, helping to guide their understanding and expectations per project

Environment: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (raw, jQuery and a custom in-house library), PHP, Veeva CRM/ Salesforce, Exploria, Photoshop CC, Illustrator CC, SharePoint, iOS, Mac OS X, Subversion (Cornerstone)

Multimedia Developer

Red Nucleus, Hamilton, NJ

April 2013 — June 2014

- Responsible for the timely delivery of web-based eLearning applications incorporating various forms of media including image sprites, audio and video for such high-profile clients as AstraZeneca, Karl Storz, Bayer Pharmaceuticals and Roche Diagnostics
- Provided the company's first digital detailing templates and working presentations for use within the iQ.mercury platform on iPad
- Constructed several templates for use throughout each application, controlled heavily by JavaScript and JSON objects
- Prepared application themes within and full documentation on using "Articulate Storyline" including known pitfalls and effective solutions to Storyline's inherent HTML5 output errors
- Converted the company's old flash-based eLearning programs into HTML and JavaScript applications
- Built full CSS themes for each project from scratch per brand guidelines and design comps
- Seamlessly supported the latest iOS platform as well as legacy browsers down to Internet Explorer 7 **Environment:** XHTML/XML, CSS, JavaScript (raw, jQuery and a custom in-house library), iQ.mercury, Photoshop CS6, Illustrator CS6, Articulate Storyline, iOS, Microsoft Windows, Git

Web and Interactive Developer

December 2012 — Present

Graduated: May 26, 2012

Freelance, Greater Philadelphia Area

Red Nucleus

- Periodically support the company's development team in building web-based eLearning applications with quick turn-around
- Technologies used: XHTML/XML, CSS, JavaScript, Photoshop CS6, iQ.mercury, Articulate Storyline

StreamYourAd

- Responsible for the development of a startup company's HTML5- and CSS3-based website from scratch per design mockups
- Worked closely with the client to flesh out a coherent and consistently pleasing user experience
- Technologies used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (including ¡Query), PHP

GrindstoneJS / ShiftJS

- Built a light-weight (8kb minified) jQuery alternative with strikingly familiar syntax to streamline some of the more mundane JavaScript tasks in day-to-day development (GrindstoneJS)
- Built a CSS3 transition/transform-based animations library (ShiftJS)
- Constructed each with raw JavaScript, non-dependent on other libraries or plugins
- Incorporated a custom-build process via Node.js and Grunt so developers may select only the modules they require on a per-project basis
- Published each library as a package on the "node package manager" (npm) website, https://www.npmjs.com/
- Developed a mobile-first responsive website with full documentation and examples for each library

Education

University of Delaware, Newark, DE

Bachelors of Science in Management Information Systems

Concentration: Operations Management